Guide to the photograph album A tour of Palestine, 1903 from the Hisham Khatib Collection AD.MC.030_ref151
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
A Tour of Palestine, 1903 - Hisham Khatib Collection
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
AD.MC.030_ref151
26 Leaves - An album of 24 albumen photographs and one postcard.
Generally good, some brittle and warped.
An album of albumen photographs taken during a tour of Palestine in 1903. The Hisham Khatib Collection on the Holy Land and region is one of the largest collections of Middle Eastern photography still in private hands. It contains hundreds of 19th century original albumen photographic prints as well as many travel albums of the same period and early 20th century with hundreds of black and white photographs and postcards. The collection contains photography from dozens of photographers, but the albumen prints are mostly the work of the Bonfils family, Francis Frith, Francis Bedford, Matson photo Service, American Colony, Zangaki Brothers, and Frank Mason Good. Dr. Hisham Khatib has spent over 40 years amassing a vast and historically valuable collection of representations of the Near East, including the Holy Lands, including Palestine, Jordan, Turkey, Syria and Egypt. The artworks in this extraordinary collection include paintings, prints, maps, books, photographs, as well as postcards. A large part of Dr. Khatib's collection consists of rare photographic prints: he has over 3,000 images. See main collection http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/akkasah/ad_mc_030/
Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151
Content Description
An album of 24 albumen photographs and one postcard.
Hisham Khatib Collection total - 2,930 photographs and postcards (both individual prints and contained within albums) focussed on the Near East, including the Holy Land, Palestine, Jordan, Turkey, Syria and Egypt as well as a very small number from Europe.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Biographical / Historical
The Hisham Khatib Collection on the Holy Land and region is one of the largest collections of Middle Eastern photography still in private hands. It contains hundreds of 19th century original albumen photographic prints as well as many travel albums of the same period and early 20th century with hundreds of black and white photographs and postcards. The collection contains photography from dozens of photographers, but the albumen prints are mostly the work of the Bonfils family, Francis Frith, Francis Bedford, Matson photo Service, American Colony, Zangaki Brothers, and Frank Mason Good.
Dr. Hisham Khatib has spent over 40 years amassing a vast and historically valuable collection of representations of the Near East, including the Holy Lands, including Palestine, Jordan, Turkey, Syria and Egypt. The artworks in this extraordinary collection include paintings, prints, maps, books, photographs, as well as postcards. A large part of Dr. Khatib's collection consists of rare photographic prints: he has over 3,000 images.
Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Palestine; Landscapes; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Travel
- A Tour of Palestine, 1903
  - Front Outside Cover of Photo Album., March 1903; ref151_000001; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Palestine
  - Inside Cover of Photo Album (With Note Dedicated to Aunt Georgie)., March 1903; ref151_000002; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    English Writing; Palestine; Printed Materials
  - Athens with the Acropolis in the background., March 1903; ref151_000003; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Acropolis of Athens; Athens, Greece; Buildings; Architecture; English Writing
  - Smyrna (Izmir)., March 1903; ref151_000004; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Children; Women; Izmir, Turkey; Outdoors; Buildings; Landscapes; Smyrna
  - Nazareth (Mount Tabor in background)., March 1903; ref151_000005; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Nazareth; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Mount Tabor/Jabal at-Tur; Landscapes; Religious Sites; English Writing; Palestine
  - Church of the Workshop, Nazareth (St. Joseph's Church)., March 1903; ref151_000006; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Nazareth; Churches; Religious Sites; Religious Imagery; English Writing; Palestine
  - Women fetching Water, near Cana., March 1903; ref151_000007; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Women; Children; Kafr Kanna, Galilee; Galilee; Water; Outdoors; Palestine; Carriages/Coaches; Horses; Animals
  - The Sea of Tiberias (Sea of Galilee)., March 1903; ref151_000008; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Sea of Galilee/Lake Tiberias; Landscapes; Palestine; Galilee; Seas; Lakes
  - Capernaum., March 1903; ref151_000009; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Galilee; Landscapes; Buildings; Palestine
  - Jacob's Well., March 1903; ref151_000010; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Palestine; Nablus; Religious Sites; Landscapes; Outdoors; Men; Women; Buildings; Regional/National Dress; Hats
  - Jerusalem from the Temple area., March 1903; ref151_000011; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Jerusalem; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Buildings; Landscapes; Architecture; Palestine
  - Via Dolorosa., March 1903; ref151_000012; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Jerusalem; Buildings; Architecture; Religious Sites; Streets/Roads; Palestine
  - Outside the walls of Jerusalem., March 1903; ref151_000013; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Jerusalem; Architecture; Camels; Animals; Palestine
  - The Mount of Olives. Garden of Gethsemane (enclosure) in centre., March 1903; ref151_000014; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Mount of Olives/Jabal al-Zaytun, Jerusalem; Gardens; Gethsemane, Jerusalem; Buildings; Landscapes; Architecture; Religious Sites; Palestine
  - The Garden of Gethsemane., March 1903; ref151_000015; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; English Writing; Photographic Prints; Gardens; Gethsemane, Jerusalem; Landscapes; Men; Palestine; Priests/Clergymen; Men
  - The Garden of Gethsemane., March 1903; ref151_000016; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Gethsemane, Jerusalem; Religious Sites; Architecture; Palestine
  - The Mount of Temptation., March 1903; ref151_000017; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Mount Quarantania/Jabal al-Qarantal, Jericho; Mountains/Hills; Religious Sites; Landscapes; Palestine
  - The Dead Sea., March 1903; ref151_000018; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; English Writing; Photographic Prints; Dead Sea; Landscapes; Men; Women; Outdoors; Boats/Ships; Palestine; Umbrellas/Parasols; Lakes; Hats
  - The Jordan River., March 1903; ref151_000019; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Jordan River; Landscapes; English Writing; Rivers; Palestine
  - Bethany., March 1903; ref151_000020; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Al-Eizariya/Bethany; Buildings; Architecture; Carriages/Coaches; Houses; Palestine; Horses; Animals
  - A group of people at an archaeological site in Bethany., March 1903; ref151_000021; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Men; Women; Outdoors; Al-Eizariya/Bethany; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Religious Sites; Buildings; Umbrellas/Parasols; Hats; Palestine
  - Tomb of Lazarus., March 1903; ref151_000022; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Outdoors; Buildings; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Religious Sites; Men; Tombs/Mausoleums; West Bank; Palestine; Al-Eizariya/Bethany
  - Bethlehem from Rachel's Tomb, showing road to Hebron on right., March 1903; ref151_000023; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Bethlehem; Streets/Roads; English Writing; Landscapes; Buildings; Religious Sites; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Tombs/Mausoleums; Bilal bin Rabah Mosque/Rachel's Tomb; Mosques; Palestine
  - Bethlehem from the Tower., March 1903; ref151_000024; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; English Writing; Bethlehem; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Landscapes; Palestine
  - House of Simon the Tanner at Jaffa., March 1903; ref151_000025; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Jaffa; Religious Sites; Men; Women; Outdoors; Architecture; Buildings; Palestine; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Regional/National Dress; Fez/Tarboush; Hats
  - The Pyramids and the Sphinx., March 1903; ref151_000026; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Pyramids; Camels; Men; Women; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Outdoors; Giza, Egypt; Regional/National Dress
  - A lane in Bethlehem., March 1903; ref151_000027; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
    Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Bethlehem; Streets/Roads; Men; Women; Children; Outdoors; Sheep; Shepherds; Buildings; Architecture; Regional/National Dress; Palestine; Animals
  - Back Outside Cover of Photo Album., March 1903; ref151_000028; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
  - Letter to Hisham Khatib part 1., March 1903; ref151_000029; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)
  - Letter to Hisham Khatib part 2., March 1903; ref151_000030; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref151)